班長大槻に挑む４５組
マックスの張り
The 45s challenge Foreman Ohtsuki!
They bet to the max!
What? Half a million!?
何？50万？
５万じゃなくて50万か？
Not just fifty thou, half a million!?
Everyone else kicked into Kaiji's bet and made it half a million!
カイジの張りに
他の５人も乗っかって50万？
The Magic Dice
４５組が全財産で ぶつかってきた
The 45s are all in!
再び賭場を
幾重にも取り囲む大観衆
Once again, the crowd presses around the players!
１振り50万ペリカ
いや 倍づけ３倍づけだってある
Half a million in one bet!
No! They could win double, even triple!
ヘタしたら100万150万のバチが
So a million, even a million and a half is at stake!
すげえ　すげえよ あんた
Holy shit! Hooooly shit!
すげえ　すげえ
You're amazing!
これが狙いか
Is this what he's after?
ダラダラ張るのではなく こういう
劇的というか強烈な張りをすれば
If he makes one huge showy bet like this rather than chipping away...
勝っても負けてもヒーロー
He's a hero, whether he wins or loses!
バカどもが祭り上げてくれる
The idiots are making a show of it. Fine!
結果 伝説じみた逸話が残る
So you want them to be talking about you?
あんたに親が回るのを
待ってたんだ
I've been waiting for you to deal!
I don't care about your lackeys, I'm after the head honcho.
俺が倒したいのは腰巾着じゃなく
暴利をむさぼるタヌキ
あんたからなんだよ
You're it!
ふざけおって　こいつ！
Give me a fucking break!
いや… いやいや　乗せられるな
No, wait! Don't get caught up in it!
落ち着け　止めろ　心を止めろ！
Calm down! Don't get so excited!
ここは腰を落とすんだ
そしてよく考えろ
Settle down and think it over!
そんな伝説づくりや
わし憎さだけで
They wouldn't bet that much just to play for they crowd or because they're pissed at me.
この張りが あり得るかどうか
さっき やじ馬も言っとったが
Yajima's right.
チンチロは張った額以上負ける
倍払い３倍払いもある
In chinchiro, you can easily lose double, even triple your bet.
And they're going all in with half a million?
それを全財産50万張り
ふざけるな
Give me a fucking break!
Yes! It's absurd!
そう　あり得るはずがないのだ
何の勝算もなく張れる金ではない
No one would make this bet without their victory already assured!
いや あるのだ
何か勝つ勝算 勝つ算段が
No, he does!
He has to have some kind of reason, some belief he'll win!
は… ってことは
嗅ぎつけたってことか
Meaning...
Has he found the secret of my winning chinchiro?
わしの常勝チンチロの秘密
魔法の賽を
My magic dice!?
Hey, over here!
おお　こっちだ こっちだ
おっ　何すか こんな時間に
It's late. What do you want?
ヘヘヘ
聞かれちゃまずい話もあるさ
I've got something I don't want overheard.
Sit right down.
まあ座って 座って
仕上がってきたんだ
I finally got that thing I ordered a few months ago!
数ヵ月前に注文しておいたものが
やっとな
２回の外出券を使って得た お宝だ
These babies cost me two furloughs to get my hands on.
わしらが今やってる博打 チンチロ
You know how we've been playing chinchiro?
それを常勝へと導く賽
These dice will lead us to victory!
They're the 4-5-6 dice!
シゴロ賽？
4-5-6 dice?
These dice don't have a 1, 2, or 3.
この賽には
１ ２ ３の目はないんだ
４の裏は４　５の裏は５
６の裏は６
The opposite side of 4 is 4! 5 is 5! And 6 is 6!
間違ってもヒフミなんて出ない
おお
No matter what, 1-2-3 will never come up!
And when you roll these, you always get a valid hand.
これを振ると 目は１回で必ず出て
最悪でも４の目という優れ物
ウフフフ
At the very worst, you roll a 4.
もちろん見てのとおり
ゾロ目シゴロが合わせて３割３分
Just like this says!
33% of all rolls are either 4-5-6 or triples!
３度振って１回は出現する計算
One or the other will show up every third roll!
え！
ちょっと見せてください
Show me that!
俺も！
え…
Me too!
ゆ… 夢の出目だ
これなら圧勝っすよ 班長
It's like I'm dreaming!
We can clean house with these, boss!
フフフ こいつを使おうじゃないか
Let's give 'em a shot.
ちょこちょこっと
ここぞという場面で
Y'know, every now and then.
When things need to turn out like this.
So, how about it?
どうだ？
いいっすね
Sounds great!
案外 分からんもんだろ
動いてると
It's pretty hard to pick up on it when they're in motion, too.
しかしピンの目の
赤がないってのは…
But there's no red from the snake eyes...
大丈夫 大丈夫　賭場は暗いんだ
Don't worry.
It's nice and dark where we gamble.
それに いつも
これを使うわけじゃない
And we won't be using them all the time anyway.
We'll only use them when it's do-or-die.
この賽は あくまでも
ここ一番の時だけ
となれば 誰も気がつきゃせん
もともと こんなことは
If we do that, no one's gonna notice.
Hell, they'll never even think to check.
奴らの想像外
はあ
その上 この賽は目が出た後も
何ら不自然さがない
They won't be able to notice after, either.
サイコロというか立方体は
誰がどう見ても
Dice are a cube! No matter what angle you look at them from, you only see three sides.
いっぺんに３面までしか見えない
その範囲の中では
この賽は あくまで正常
Just from looking at them, these dice appear perfectly fine!
はあ
面白かろう
Sounds great, huh?
白日の下に
イカサマ賽をさらしながら
We do it in broad daylight, and no one even realizes they're fake!
一人一人の目からは
通常の賽にしか見えぬという
このカラクリ
逆方向に回り込みでも
されない限り
Just as long as they don't get behind us...
しかし…
あ？
But...
If the dealer wins with his first roll, he leaves the dice in the bowl while he collects.
シゴロとかの総取りの時は
しばらく賽をどんぶりに残し
それで金の受け取りを
することになりますよね
それってちょっと危険っていうか
That's pretty risky, but the dealer rushing to pocket the dice isn't much better.
親がコソコソ
賽を拾うっていうのは
その点はルール改正で乗り切ろう
え？
Let's change the rules to deal with it!
親がどんな目でも子も振れる
チンチロにしようじゃないか
Why not make the players roll no matter what the dealer gets?
つまり わしの右隣にいるお前が
すぐ賽を拾ってしまえばいいんだ
You sit to my right, and swap the dice out right away.
そして処理する
いいっすね
And we win.
That sounds great!
それなら…
いやあ 面白いっすよ 班長
Then...
That sounds amazing, boss!
He figured it out!
こいつ 気がつきおったか
このシゴロ賽に
This piece of human trash figured out my 4-5-6 dice!
クズの分際で
わしが心血注いだ換金博打
The gambling trick I worked so hard to get!
この常勝チンチロの仕組みに
The way I always win at chinchiro!
カイジ　カイジ…
Kaiji! Kaiji!
しかし どうして分かった
But how did he figure it out?
奴が大敗　４５組に転落した
あの時の博打では
It didn't seem like he noticed the night he lost big and joined the ranks of the 45s.
気づいたような そぶりはなかった
And since then he hasn't gambled.
あの後は一切
博打に参加していないわけだし
そうか 三好か　こいつのメモだな
Is that it? Miyoshi?
It has to be his notepad!
そのメモで嗅ぎつけてきおったか
He figured it out with his notes!
チッ　少しナメすぎた
I wasn't quite cautious enough...
あんなこと許さなければよかった
I should have stopped him.
クソッ
Dammit!
Oh well. If I'm busted, I'm busted.
しょうがない
バレちまった以上しょうがない
シゴロ賽を使わず しのぐしかない
I'll have to play without the 4-5-6 dice.
奴らの狙いは わしがシゴロ賽を
使ったその現場を押さえて
They're trying to catch me rolling dirty.
わしに恥をかかせ かつ
Trying to embarrass me. And!
That way they think they'll snatch up two or three times their bet!
その落とし前として 張った額の
２倍３倍をふんだくろうって魂胆
その手には乗らん
I won't let that happen!
いけいけ！
振れ 振れ 班長から
He's rolling! It's the boss's turn to roll!
そうだ そうだ
まずは班長から50万振り
Yeah! The boss is rolling for half a mil!
クソッ
いつもなら難なく勝てるのに
This would usually be so easy...
But I let down my guard a little bit, and these idiots...
ちょっとした油断のせいで
こんなバカ
クズ相手に あろうことか普通の賽
Now I have to use normal dice on this scum!
Dammit!
クソ　クソ　クソ！
Dammit! Dammit!
I have to rely on Lady Luck!
運否天賦の博打を
しなきゃならんとは
なんたる不覚　無念
What a mistake! I can't believe it!
But I have to!
しかし仕方ない
気づかれたら仕方ない
They've figured it out, so I have to!
うー　かあ！
ここだ　ここで出るはず
Now!
He'll do it now!
奴が気づいているなら ここで出る
If he really knows, he'll do something now!
賽を押さえに行く初期動作
予兆 気配が
He'll get ready to grab the dice!
Some sign... Some feeling...
What? He's sitting still!?
奴が動かない　では…
He's not moving!? Why!?
一体…
班長大槻　出目なし
The foreman Ohtsuki rolls a bust!
ああ 危ねえ
ヤバい
Wow, that was close!
He almost had it!
もう少しでシゴロ　命拾い
That's almost a 4-5-6!
What a close call!
カイジさん
Kaiji...
クソッ
Shit!
どういうことだ
What's going on!?
奴は今 動かなかった
He didn't flinch at all!
シゴロ賽を押さえようって
そんな動きが
Didn't try to grab the dice!
他の連中も
ただ目が出なかったことを
And the others just seem relieved that it didn't come up 4-5-6!
安堵しているようにしか見えない
普通のサイコロだったという
ショックがない
They're not shocked at me using normal dice!
待てよ　ってことはひょっとして
Wait!
Am... Am I...
杞憂なのか
奴は気づいてないのか 何も
Am I just worrying too much?
Do they not realize?
Not realize anything at all?
気づいてない？気づいてない？
Don't they realize!?
気づいてない？気づいてない…
ひょっとして奴は このシゴロ賽の
トリックにまだ気づいてない
Maybe they haven't caught on the the 4-5-6 dice!
つまり思い過ごし　独り相撲
Then I was just overworrying! It was all paranoia!
すべては わしの独り相撲
No, wait...
いや 待てよ
そういえば今の第１投は
すべて諦めて振ったから
Really, I had given up before I rolled...
ポケットにシゴロ賽を取りに行く
そんな動作をしなかった
So I didn't even reach for the 4-5-6 dice in my pocket!
That's it?
そこか
I didn't do that, so they held off on my first roll?
そのそぶりがなかったのを見て
１投目はなしと踏んだのか
Then...
なら見せてやろうじゃないか
I'll show them something that looks like a dice swap!
それらしい動きを きっちり
Just like one!
All right, my second roll!
よし　第２投だ
Here's my second roll!
いくぜ ２投目
I'm gonna roll 4-5-6 this time!
ここで出す きっちりシゴロを
Yeah!
いいぞ 班長
Boss! Boss!
班長　班長…
普通の賽を握った左手と
He joins his left hand, which he normally rolls with,
with his right hand, as if pulling something from his pocket!
いかにも何かを
握り込んできたかのような右手を
ガッチ
ふん…
どうだ これならどうだ
Well!? How about this!?
これならシゴロ賽使用バージョン
わし本来の動き
This is just how I'd move if I was using the 4-5-6 dice!
うー かあ！
文句あるまい
Go ahead, call me out on it!
The foreman Ohtsuki rolls for a second time!
班長大槻 ２投目
Come on!
さあ来い
The bowl is obviously closer to me!
どんぶりには明らかに
わしのほうが近いんだ
目が出てから動いては
奴はどんぶりをさらえない
He'll never be able to grab to bowl after the dice come up!
賽を押さえることはできない
So he can't get the dice!
Then he'll try to worm closer...
ならば この段階で
にじり寄ってくるはずだ
あの手か　体全体か
His hand? His whole body?
His legs? Will he shift his crouch?
それとも足？座り直してくるか
Which one? Where will he move!?
どれだ　どこが動く
動かない
He's... Not moving...
こいつ まるで動かない
The scum isn't moving...
動かない　動かない　動かない
He's not moving! He's not moving!
動かない！
He's not moving!!!
あ… ってことは
That means...
やっぱり… やっぱり違うのか
I...
I must have been wrong?
２投目も目なし
His second roll is also a bust!
He almost got a 4-5-6 again!
またシゴロのなりかけじゃんか
危ねえ
Holy shit!
ハア　助かった
ハア…
That was so close...
I was wrong! They haven't realized!
違う　気づいてない
そう考えるしかない
It's obvious now!
カイジの反応も
I can tell from Kaiji's reaction, and the idiots lined up behind him!
ガンクビ並べている
このバカどもの反応も そう
Those can't be the reactions of people who know about the 4-5-6 dice!
とてもシゴロ賽の存在を
知っている者の反応とは思えん
If they knew, they'd show shock! Despair!
知っているのならショックが
失望があるはずだ
Despair that I didn't use the 4-5-6 dice!
こっちがシゴロ賽を
使わないっていう失望が
しかし そんなもの
この連中には微塵も感じられない
But I can't feel a thing from them!
They're just staring at the bowl, not sure whether to be worried or excited!
ただ能天気にどんぶりをのぞいて
一喜一憂しているだけ
とすると この金
この大金をどう考える
Which means this money...
Why would they be betting this much?
ただのバカ張りと考えるには
あまりに
I can't believe they're just plain that dumb.
はっ 待てよ
ひょっとして奴らの狙いは
Wait. Maybe what they're after...
大槻の迷い
Ohtsuki wavers!
この迷い 迷走　それが狙いか
His wavering, his hesitation! Is this their aim!?
つまりこの金は
This money must be...
Is it to hold me back?
わしの動きを止める
抑止力のための金？
イカサマ防止の重し？
To keep me from cheating!?
要するに わしの勝負強さに対して
My luck is pretty suspicious.
不信感というか
直観的なものを感じていて
Maybe they're doing it out of a sense something's up.
何かあるのかもしれないと
考えている
重しを中に入れたとか
They think I'm using loaded dice, or magnets, or something...
磁石を仕込んだとか そんなこと
本当のネタには届いてない
They don't know the real trick!
おぼろ　何かをしているかも
しれないというレベルの
They just have a hunch!
Just a hunch that something's up! They're not sure!
おぼろな気づき
それなら問題ない
Then there's no problem!
つまり奴らのこの大金は
何かを封じ込めに来ただけなんだ
They just bet this much to scare me away from using any tricks!
要するにブラフ
気づいてるふりだけ
It's a bluff!
They're just pretending they know something's up!
There's nothing there! They don't really know!
本当は空白　気づいていない
Yeah, if they knew about the 4-5-6 dice, they'd never have been able to play dumb this long.
そりゃそうだろう
シゴロ賽に気づいたら
こうまで
そらっと ぼけてなんかいられない
まさか揃いも揃って
名優揃いってわけでもあるまい
It's not like I've got a star-studded cast of thespian geniuses lined up here.
なら
So...
いきましょう
Let's go.
いきましょう　いける いける
大丈夫ですって
Let's go!
We can do it! It'll be fine!
フッ　疑り深い沼川も そう思うか
If even Numakawa the doubter thinks so...
よし　いくか
All right!
Let's do it.
You must be scared now! That's my second near-4-5-6!
今 なりかけたのう
２度もシゴロに
上り調子
今 勢いはわしにある　フフフ
The momentum's on my side!
正気かよ　２度の目なし
Are you serious? You just busted twice in a row!
Momentum on your side? Are you nuts?
どこが上り調子だ
バカ言ってんじゃねえ
いいや いいや　予感がする
Oh, I just have a good feeling about my next roll...
三度目の正直　フフフ
Third time's the charm.
ヘッ　イカれたことを
You've got screws loose.
Face it, that ain't gonna happen.
悪いが そうは思うようには
いかねえんだよ
You're gonna bust again and lose!
目なし惨敗だよ おめえは
ハッ　虚勢を張ってどうなる
Who's he trying to fool?
下がれ
Back off.
分かるさ　もうすぐ分かる
You'll see. Ohh, you'll see.
You'll see who's right.
どちらが正しいか
フフッ　バカが
Idiot.
You're just an idiot.
やっぱり お前はバカだ
今 それを証明してやる カイジ
I'll prove it to you right now.
Kaiji!
Here I go!
出動だ
魔力 シゴロ賽　投入
I'll slip in the magic 4-5-6 dice!
This is it!
いよいよだ
３投目
His third roll!
運命の３投目
これで決まる
The fateful third roll...
This decides everything!
班長の目が決まるか
決まるか 決まるか
Will the foreman's roll settle it!?
Will it? Will it!?!
決まる　決まる…
Settle it! Settle it!
班長の慎重癖にも困ったもんだ
His own caution is messing with him.
危うく自ら転ぶところだった
He can't stand the pressure.
しかし これで安心
これで負けはない
But don't worry! With these, we can't lose!
勝つ　選択　シゴロ賽
Win! I choose you, 4-5-6 dice!
かあ！
３投目 班長大槻
The third roll! Foreman Ohtsuki's third roll!
３投目　運命の３投目
His fateful third roll!
決まる　決まる…
Settle it! Settle it!
カイジさん
Kaiji...
遺恨試合　カイジ 対 班長大槻
The grudge match between Kaiji and the foreman Ohtsuki!
In this fateful battle, the foreman's roll will be revealed in mere seconds!
その因縁の戦い
班長の目 それが決定する
あと数秒で
ああ もうダメ　苦しい
I can't take this... It hurts...
Okay, okay! They haven't noticed!
オーケー オーケー
奴らは気がついてない
They haven't noticed the 4-5-6 dice!
このシゴロ賽に気がついてない
仮に気がついたとしても この賽を
押さえられなければいいのだ
Even if they do notice, it doesn't matter as long as I keep the dice out of their hands!
If they make the slightest move for the dice, I grab 'em.
もし連中が妙な動きを
少しでも見せたら さらえばいい
俺が奴らより早くこのどんぶりを
I can get to the bowl quicker than them!
それでオーケー　問題ない
If I do that, we're fine! Nothing will happen!
問題ない
Yes!
そう　カイジからすれば
まさにそれが難関　障壁
From Kaiji's position, that's difficult, almost impossible!
This is the steepest hurdle in his attempt to beat the 4-5-6 dice!
このシゴロ賽破りの
最も厄介なハードル
逆に言えば これが班長サイドの
最後の防衛線
Looking at it the other way, it's the foreman's final defense!
Their last, absolutely vital, stronghold!
打ち破られてはいけない 最後の砦
Normally, at this point, the dice are by the foreman and easier for him to grab!
通常 この奪い合いは
賽に近い班長側に有利
If the foreman and his lackeys block the bowl, Kaiji can't grab it!
そのことに班長側が
身構えていたら
まずこの奪い合いを
カイジが制することはできない
Numakawa is first!
沼川が先だ
But at this very moment, his guard is down!
しかし虚を突けば別
あ…
このチンチロという勝負の死角
The one blind spot in the game of chinchirorin!
A mystery of psychology!
心理の死角
Kaiji can take advantage of this and change the game!
そこを突けば別
誰もが その時だけは
息をのんで見守るしかない
The audience can only watch with bated breath!
神に祈るしかない
Can only pray to God!
That time...
そんな時間
Stealing that time can change the game!
そんな時間を盗めば 別
That is... While they're rolling!
すなわち回っている時
そうだ　押さえれば 別
Yes!
If he presses then...
It changes everything!
突っ込んだ　カイジは神の時間に
手を突っ込んだ
Kaiji thrusts his hand in!
Into the time which God only knows!
Proverbs of Kaiji Returns!
Dice are a cube.
No matter what angle you look at them from,
you only see three sides.
Just from looking at them, these dice appear perfectly fine!